<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unity on Gianluca Camarca</title>
    <link>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/tags/unity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unity on Gianluca Camarca</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mars Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/mars-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/mars-kitchen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Served as a &lt;strong&gt;Gameplay Programmer&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Technical Designer&lt;/strong&gt;, acting as the bridge between creative vision and technical implementation. I owned critical parts of the optimization pipeline and led the console certification process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-technical-contributions&#34;&gt;Key Technical Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;systems-architecture--optimization&#34;&gt;Systems Architecture &amp;amp; Optimization&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runtime Lightmap Swapping:&lt;/strong&gt; Architected a custom system to enable a seamless &amp;ldquo;Endless Mode&amp;rdquo;. This allowed for instant environment changes without scene reloading, maintaining player immersion while managing memory constraints.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Virtualization:&lt;/strong&gt; Engineered an AI Virtualization System to simulate off-screen customer behavior and order generation. This maintained complex game state consistency with minimal CPU overhead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay--physics&#34;&gt;Gameplay &amp;amp; Physics&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex Mechanics Prototyping:&lt;/strong&gt; Acted as Technical Designer to implement advanced physics interactions, minigames and hand tracking gestures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Localization System:&lt;/strong&gt; Built a robust, scalable localization system supporting 5 languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;platform-engineering&#34;&gt;Platform Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PlayStation VR Porting:&lt;/strong&gt; Owned the full porting and certification pipeline for PlayStation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certification Success:&lt;/strong&gt; Successfully navigated strict &lt;strong&gt;Sony TRC (Technical Requirements Checklist)&lt;/strong&gt; standards to ensure a smooth launch on the PlayStation Store.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyverse</title>
      <link>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/polyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/polyverse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I acted as the Core Systems Architect, responsible for designing the fundamental multiplayer infrastructure and custom physics implementations. My primary focus was on ensuring deterministic simulation for networked gameplay and extending Unity&amp;rsquo;s rendering pipeline to meet specific visual requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-technical-contributions&#34;&gt;Key Technical Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;multiplayer-architecture--security&#34;&gt;Multiplayer Architecture &amp;amp; Security&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server-Authoritative Networking:&lt;/strong&gt; Engineered a robust architecture using Mirror and PlayFab. Implemented advanced Client-Side Prediction and Server Reconciliation techniques to ensure lag-free movement while maintaining strict server authority to prevent cheating in the game&amp;rsquo;s token-based economy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deterministic Simulation:&lt;/strong&gt; Wrote a custom deterministic A* Pathfinding algorithm and Behavior Tree system from scratch. By bypassing Unity’s standard non-deterministic NavMesh, I guaranteed perfectly synchronized enemy movement across all clients, eliminating desync issues common in networked PvE games.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics--controls&#34;&gt;Physics &amp;amp; Controls&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Kinematic Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; Developed a bespoke Kinematic Character Controller to handle non-standard gravity logic and complex stair traversal, areas where the default physics engine often struggles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procedural Animation:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrated the controller with an animation state machine featuring Inverse Kinematics (IK) for grounded foot placement and realistic interactions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphics-programming&#34;&gt;Graphics Programming&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URP Extension:&lt;/strong&gt; Extended the Universal Render Pipeline (URP) by writing a custom Render Feature and Render Pass. This achieved an &amp;ldquo;X-Ray&amp;rdquo; silhouette effect for characters occluded by geometry, enhancing gameplay clarity without sacrificing visual fidelity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gameplay-framework&#34;&gt;Gameplay Framework&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data-Driven Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Created a modular framework using ScriptableObjects, allowing game designers to balance weapon stats and gameplay variables independently, decoupling content creation from engineering tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metaverse — Regione Lombardia</title>
      <link>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/metaverse-regione-lombardia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/metaverse-regione-lombardia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metaverse — Regione Lombardia is a pioneering digital initiative by the Lombardy Region, designed to bring citizens closer to public institutions through immersive technology. This virtual environment allows users to explore interactive digital spaces, participate in events, and discover Lombardy&amp;rsquo;s rich cultural heritage—breaking down physical barriers and enabling new forms of engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the Metaverse, users can create personalized avatars, meet others, visit virtual exhibitions, and attend public events. Notably, the platform features a digital recreation of Piazza Città di Lombardia, offering a safe and privacy-respecting space for shared experiences. The debut exhibition, &amp;ldquo;Incontri nel Metaverso – Tradizioni e saperi lombardi,&amp;rdquo; developed in collaboration with the Archive of Ethnography and Social History (AESS), celebrates the region&amp;rsquo;s traditions and roots through objects and stories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acryptia</title>
      <link>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/acryptia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gi4nlucac.github.io/portfolio/projects/acryptia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-role&#34;&gt;My Role&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Core Gameplay Programmer, I was responsible for the architectural design of the card battle system and the backend integration. My focus was on creating a secure, server-authoritative environment while pushing the visual boundaries of WebGL through custom shader work and particle integration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-technical-contributions&#34;&gt;Key Technical Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-architecture--design-patterns&#34;&gt;Core Architecture &amp;amp; Design Patterns&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable Card Logic:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented the Strategy Design Pattern to decouple card behaviors from execution flow. This ensured code maintainability and allowed for the easy addition of new card mechanics without refactoring core systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend Security:&lt;/strong&gt; Developed a Server-Authoritative Logic layer utilizing PlayFab and Mirror. Managed critical operations—including deck population, shuffling, and match validation—strictly server-side to prevent client-side manipulation and ensure competitive integrity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphics--optimization&#34;&gt;Graphics &amp;amp; Optimization&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Skinning System:&lt;/strong&gt; Created a custom RGB-mask Shader solution to handle UI customization. This allowed UI elements to be recolored at runtime via ScriptableObjects, drastically reducing the build size by eliminating the need for duplicate textures for different skins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI VFX Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcame standard UI limitations by implementing particle systems directly within the Unity 2D Canvas hierarchy, enhancing the &amp;ldquo;game feel&amp;rdquo; and visual feedback without sacrificing sorting layer control.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tooling--pipeline&#34;&gt;Tooling &amp;amp; Pipeline&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designer Workflow:&lt;/strong&gt; Built custom Editor Tools, including a Deck Configurator and balancing utilities. These tools accelerated the content iteration loop, allowing designers to tweak meta-game values without engineering dependency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
